<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>parliaments | Thomas Winzen</title>
    <link>https://thomaswinzen.github.io/tag/parliaments/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://thomaswinzen.github.io/tag/parliaments/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>parliaments</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2021 Thomas Winzen</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://thomaswinzen.github.io/images/icon_hu02b2264248573ab4fcd6898e7f9e3b4f_17401_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>parliaments</title>
      <link>https://thomaswinzen.github.io/tag/parliaments/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Institutional Position of National Parliaments in the European Union: Developments, Explanations, Effects</title>
      <link>https://thomaswinzen.github.io/publication/winzen-npreview-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thomaswinzen.github.io/publication/winzen-npreview-2021/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> The Rise of International Parliaments: Strategic Legitimation in International Organizations</title>
      <link>https://thomaswinzen.github.io/publication/schimmelfennig2020rise/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Dec 2020 12:33:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thomaswinzen.github.io/publication/schimmelfennig2020rise/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Parliaments Beyond the State</title>
      <link>https://thomaswinzen.github.io/project/parliaments/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Nov 2020 12:23:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thomaswinzen.github.io/project/parliaments/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Can parliaments contribute to democratic and legitimate governance in the European Union and international organizations? When and why can we expect political actors to realize the democratic potential that parliaments might have? If they do, what are the political and policy consequences?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>International Parliamentary Institutions Dataset (IPIdata)</title>
      <link>https://thomaswinzen.github.io/datasets/ipidata/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thomaswinzen.github.io/datasets/ipidata/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The International Parliamentary Institutions Dataset (IPIdata) codes information on the institutional authority and organization of 54 international parliamentary institutions (IPIs) from 1945 to 2019. The data collection was funded by the Swiss National Science Foundation via the NCCR Democracy. The data and documentation is available via the link above. Please email me or one of the other authors if you have questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you use the data in your research, please cite:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Schimmelfennig, Frank, Thomas Winzen, Tobias Lenz, Jofre Rocabert, Lori Crasnic, Cristina Gherasimov, Jana Lipps, and Densua Mumford. 2020. &lt;em&gt;The Rise of International Parliaments: Strategic Legitimation in International Organizations&lt;/em&gt;. Oxford: Oxford University Press.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>National Parliaments in the EU Dataset (NPdata)</title>
      <link>https://thomaswinzen.github.io/datasets/npdata/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thomaswinzen.github.io/datasets/npdata/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The National Parliaments in the European Union Dataset (NPdata) codes formal rights and mechanisms for parliamentary involvement in EU affairs from 1952 to 2020. It contains information on oversight institutions, which specify parliamentary information and participation rights in relation to the government’s involvement in EU policymaking. NPdata also includes information on parliamentary rights in the European Semester (ES) and decision-making of the European Stability Mechanism (ESM).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The data is available via &lt;a href=&#34;https://dataverse.harvard.edu/dataverse/npdata&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Harvard Dataverse&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you use the data on oversight institutions, please cite &lt;a href=&#34;https://thomaswinzen.github.io/publication/winzen-national-2012/&#34;&gt;Winzen (2012)&lt;/a&gt; for data before 2010 and &lt;a href=&#34;https://thomaswinzen.github.io/publication/winzen-npreview-2021/&#34;&gt;Winzen (2021)&lt;/a&gt; for data from 2010-2020.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Winzen, Thomas. 2012. National Parliamentary Control of European Union Affairs: A Cross-National and Longitudinal Comparison. &lt;em&gt;West European Politics&lt;/em&gt; 35 (3): 657–72.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Winzen, Thomas. 2021. The Institutional Position of National Parliaments in the European Union: Developments, Explanations, Effects. &lt;em&gt;Journal of European Public Policy&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you use the data on parliamentary rights in the ES and ESM, please cite &lt;a href=&#34;https://thomaswinzen.github.io/publication/rittberger-parlamentarismus-2015/&#34;&gt;Rittberger and Winzen (2015)&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://thomaswinzen.github.io/publication/winzen-npreview-2021/&#34;&gt;Winzen (2021)&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rittberger, Berthold, and Thomas Winzen. 2015. Parlamentarismus Nach Der Krise: Die Vertiefung Parlamentarischer Asymmetrie in Der Reformierten Wirtschafts- Und Währungsunion. &lt;em&gt;Politische Vierteljahresschrift&lt;/em&gt; 56 (3): 430–56.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Winzen, Thomas. 2021. The Institutional Position of National Parliaments in the European Union: Developments, Explanations, Effects. &lt;em&gt;Journal of European Public Policy&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Parlamentarismus nach der Krise: Die Vertiefung parlamentarischer Asymmetrie in der reformierten Wirtschafts- und Währungsunion</title>
      <link>https://thomaswinzen.github.io/publication/rittberger-parlamentarismus-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thomaswinzen.github.io/publication/rittberger-parlamentarismus-2015/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>National parliamentary control of European Union affairs: a cross-national and longitudinal comparison</title>
      <link>https://thomaswinzen.github.io/publication/winzen-national-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thomaswinzen.github.io/publication/winzen-national-2012/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
